Guide to the Witness to Guantanamo Video Collection, 2009-2017 RL.11691
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Witness to Guantanamo Video Collection
2009-2017
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11691
10 Terabytes High (ProRes) and low (MP4) resolution Apple MOV files.
One hundred fifty-three video files of interviews with 149 former detainees and others -- attornies, chaplains, guards, government officials, human rights advocates, journalists -- who witnessed the impact of the Guantanamo Bay detention center in the post-911 years. An additional 346 files, short clips extracted from the interviews featured on the Witness to Guantanamo site, are also included.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by interviewee surname.
Biographical / Historical
Following the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, the American naval base at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, became the site of the detention center for suspected al Qaeda and Taliban operatives. Peter Jan Honigsberg, a professor at the University of San Francisco School of Law, began Witness to Guantanamo (WtG) in fall 2008, after realizing that no one was filming, collecting and preserving the voices and stories of Guantanamo. He modelled Witness to Guantanamo after grassroots truth commissions and the Shoah Foundation's collection of Holocaust survivor testimonies.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Witness to Guantanamo Video Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2018.
Collection Overview
One hundred fifty-three video files of interviews with 149 former detainees and others -- attornies, chaplains, guards, government officials, human rights advocates, journalists -- who witnessed the impact of the Guantanamo Bay detention center in the post-911 years. A wide range of topics includes physical and psychological torture, religious faith, medical care, interrogation, trials, and women at Guantanamo. An additional 346 files, short clips extracted from the interviews featured on the Witness to Guantanamo site, are also included.
- Interviews, 2009-2017; 10,000 Gigabytes secure server
  Conditions Governing Access
  See specific interview for access restrictions.
  Arrangement
  Arranged by interviewee name.
  Scope and Contents
  Interviews with 149 former detainees and others -- attornies, chaplains, guards, government officials, human rights advocates, journalists -- who witnessed the impact of the Guantanamo Bay detention center in the post-911 years. A wide range of topics includes physical and psychological torture, religious faith, medical care, interrogation, trials, and women at Guantanamo. Short clips extracted from the interviews, used on the Witness to Guantanamo website, are listed where available.
  - Abbas, Rushan, 2010-01-05; 2:03:42
    Rushan Abbas, female, age 42, was an interpreter for the Uyghur detainees in Guantanamo from 2002-2003. When the men were released, she stayed with them in Bermuda for two weeks to help them readjust.
    - Abbas, Rushan - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file RushanAbbas.mov)
    - Abbas, Rushan - short clip - constitution (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Rushan_constitution.mp4)
    - Abbas, Rushan - short clip - forefathers (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Rushan_forefathers.mp4)
    - Abbas, Rushan - short clip - interrogation (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file RushanAbbas_interrogation.mp4)
    - Abbas, Rushan - short clip - InterrogationTechniques (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file RushanAbbas_InterrogationTechniques.mp4)
  - Abbasi, Feroz Ali, 2010-08-07; 2:18:44
    Feroz Ali Abbasi, male, age 30, British, was detained in Guantanamo from January 10, 2002 until January 25, 2005, when he was returned to Britain.
    - Abbasi, Feroz Ali - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file FerozAliAbbasi.mov)
    - Abbasi, Feroz Ali - short clip - BeyondtheVeil (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FerozAliAbbasi_BeyondtheVeil.mp4)
    - Abbasi, Feroz Ali - short clip - BeyondtheVeil (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FerozAliAbbasi_BeyondtheVeil.mp4)
    - Abbasi, Feroz Ali - short clip - BeyondtheVeil (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FerozAliAbbasi_BeyondtheVeil_short30fp.mp4)
    - Abbasi, Feroz Ali - short clip - BeyondtheVeil (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FerozAliAbbasi_BeyondtheVeil_short.mp4)
    - Abbasi, Feroz Ali - short clip - BeyondtheVeil2 (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BeyondtheVeil2.mp4)
    - Abbasi, Feroz Ali - short clip - EnduringGuantanamo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FerozAliAbbasi_EnduringGuantanamo.mp4)
    - Abbasi, Feroz Ali - short clip - testname (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file testname.mp4)
  - Abd al Mahsen al Zamel, Adel Zamel, 2011-01-02; 1:20:22
    Adel Zamel Abd al Mahsen al Zamel, male, age 47, Kuwaiti, was detained in Guantanamo from May 1, 2002 until November 2, 2005, when he was returned to Kuwait and later acquitted in a Kuwaiti court.
    - Abd al Mahsen al Zamel, Adel Zamel - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AdelZamelAbdalMahsenalZamel.mov)
  - Abdulahat, Salahidin, 2010-05-30; 1:25:57
    Interview may be accessed only via the electronic records and media computer in the Rubenstein Library reading room.
    Salahidin Abdulahat, male, age 32, a Uyghur from the Xinjiang autonomous region, was detained in Guantanamo from 2002 until June 11, 2009, when he was transferred to Bermuda.
    - Abdulahat, Salahidin - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file SalahidinAbdulahat.mov)
  - Abraham, Stephen, 2010-03-11; 2:33:20
    Stephen Abraham, male, age unknown, served with the Office for the Administrative Review of Enemy Combatants from September 2004 through March 2005, and was the first officer to publicly criticize the operations of the Combatant Status Review Tribunals. His affidavit was key to the United States Supreme Court decision in Al Odah v. United States, and subsequently Boumediene v. Bush.
    - Abraham, Stephen - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file StephenAbraham.mov)
    - Abraham, Stephen - short clip - Blood on Our Hands (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Steven Abraham-Blood on Our Hands.mp4)
    - Abraham, Stephen - short clip - CSRTs Were Advisory (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Steven Abraham-CSRTs Were Advisory.mp4)
  - Adams, John, 2012-09-21; 1:43:57
    John Adams, male, age 58, was an Army Brigadier General, and on September 11, 2001, was serving as Deputy Director for European Policy in the Office of the Secretary of Defense.
    - Adams, John - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file JohnAdams.mov)
    - Adams, John - short clip - ClosingGuantanamo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file JohnAdams_ClosingGuantanamo.mp4)
  - Adil, Ahmed, 2009-08-04; 1:41:27
    Ahmed Adil, male, age 33, a Uyghur from the Xinjiang autonomous region, was detained in Guantanamo from early 2002 to May 5, 2006, when he was released to Albania. In May 2005, his Combatant Status Review Tribunal determined he was not an enemy combatant, but he was not relased until the following year.
    - Adil, Ahmed - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AhmedAdil.mov)
  - Ahmed, Ruhal, 2009-08-16; 2:27:29
    Ruhal Ahmed, male, age 28, British, was detained in Guantanamo from February 11, 2002 until March 9, 2004, when he was returned to Britain, and released without charge.
    - Ahmed, Ruhal - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file RuhalAhmed.mov)
    - Ahmed, Ruhal - short clip - PBSandwich (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file RuhalAhmed_PBSandwich.mp4)
    - Ahmed, Ruhal - short clip - Shampoo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file RuhalAhmed_Shampoo.mp4)
    - Ahmed, Ruhal - short clip - WitnessingAttemptedSuicide (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file RuhalAhmed_WitnessingAttemptedSuicide.mp4)
  - Aouzar, Mohamed, 2012-07-12; 1:36:56
    Interview may be accessed only with donor approval, via the electronic records and media computer in the Rubenstein Library reading room.
    Mohamed Aouzar, male, age 32, Moroccan, was detained in Guantanamo from February 4, 2002 until July 31, 2004 when he was returned to Morocco, where he was eventually acquitted in 2007.
    - Aouzar, Mohamed - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MohamedAouzarShadowed.mov)
  - Arendt, Christopher, 2011-04-30; 2:31:30
    Christopher Arendt, male, age 27, was stationed as a guard in Guantanamo for 10 months beginning in January 2004. After finishing his tour in 2008, he gave public testimony about the mistreatment of detainees in Guantanamo.
    - Arendt, Christopher - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file ChrisArendt.mov)
    - Arendt, Christopher - short clip - AttackedpByADetainee (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ChrisArendt_AttackedpByADetainee.mp4)
    - Arendt, Christopher - short clip - SexualHarassmentAndRapeAtGuantanamo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ChrisArendt_SexualHarassmentAndRapeAtGuantanamo.mp4)
    - Arendt, Christopher - short clip - VideotapingForcedCellExtractions (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ChrisArendt_VideotapingForcedCellExtractions.mp4)
  - Asam, Zakirjan, 2009-08-05; 1:46:40
    Zakirjan Asam, male, age 35, Russian and Uzbekistani, was detained in Guantanamo from June 14, 2002 until November 17, 2006, when he was released to Albania. During his Combatant Status Review Tribunal, he was determined to not be an enemy combatant.
    - Asam, Zakirjan - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file ZakirjanAsam.mov)
    - Asam, Zakirjan - short clip - redsticker (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Zakirjan_redsticker.mp4)
    - Asam, Zakirjan - short clip - watermelon (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Zakirjan_watermelon.mp4)
  - Ashraf, Michael, circa 2015
    - Ashraf, Michael - short clip - GuantanamosDamagedFamilies (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AshrafMichael_GuantanamosDamagedFamilies.mp4)
    - Ashraf, Michael - short clip - GuantanamosDamagedFamilies-review (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AshrafMichael_GuantanamosDamagedFamilies-review.mp4)
    - Ashraf, Michael - short clip - NotFitToBeaTerrorist (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AshrafMichael_NotFitToBeaTerrorist.mp4)
    - Ashraf, Michael - short clip - NotFitToBeaTerrorist-review (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AshrafMichael_NotFitToBeaTerrorist-review.mp4)
    - Ashraf, Michael - short clip - WasGuantanmoJustified (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AshrafMichael_WasGuantanmoJustified.mp4)
    - Ashraf, Michael - short clip - WasGuantanmoJustified-review (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AshrafMichael_WasGuantanmoJustified-review.mp4)
  - Azmi, Saad Madi Saad al, 2011-01-03; 1:47:45
    Saad Madi Saad al Azmi, male, age 31, Kuwaiti, was detained in Guantanamo from May 1, 2002 until November 2, 2005 when he was returned to Kuwait, tried and acquitted.
    - Azmi, Saad Madi Saad al - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file SaadMadiSaadalAzmi.mov)
  - Baker, Sean, 2011-10-21; 2:21:12
    Sean Baker, male, age 45, was a prison guard at Guantanamo beginning in November 2002. On January 24, 2003, during a role-playing exercise to train soldiers in a forced cell extraction (erf), he played the role of a detainee. He was severely beaten by fellow soldiers who believed he was an actual detainee, and sustained a brain injury, vision loss, and ongoing seizures.
    - Baker, Sean - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file SeanBaker.mov)
  - Banna, Jamil El-, 2011-08-02; 0:30:09
    Jamil El-Banna, male, age 49, a Jordanian citizen of Palestinian descent, was detained in Guantanamo from March 2003 until December 19, 2007, when he was released to Britain.
    - Banna, Jamil El- - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file JamilEl-Banna.mov)
    - Banna, Jamil El- - short clip - WhenIRememberICan'tSpeak (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file JamilElBamma_WhenIRememberICan'tSpeak.mp4)
  - Basil, Akhtar Qasem, 2009-08-04; 2:01:33
    Akhtar Qasem Basil, male, age 34, a Uyghur from the Xinjiang autonomous region, was detained in Guantanamo from June 10, 2002 until May 5, 2006, when he was released to Albania. In 2004-2005, his Combatant Status Review Tribunal determined he was not an enemy combatant, but he was not released until the following year.
    - Basil, Akhtar Qasem - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AkhtarQasemBasil.mov)
  - Begg, Moazzam, 2009-08-17; 2:04:16
    Moazzam Begg, male, age 41, British, was detained in Guantanamo from February 6, 2003 until January 25, 2005, when he was returned without charge to Britain.
    - Begg, Moazzam - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MoazzamBegg.mov)
    - Begg, Moazzam - short clip - humancontact (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MoazzamBegg_humancontact.mp4)
    - Begg, Moazzam - short clip - HumanContact (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MoazzamBegg_HumanContact.mp4)
    - Begg, Moazzam - short clip - HumanContactshorter (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MoazzamBegg_HumanContactshorter.mp4)
    - Begg, Moazzam - short clip - worstfear (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Moazzam_worstfear.mp4)
  - Bellinger, John, 2013-12-17; 1:01:49
    John Bellinger, male, age unknown, held several senior Presidential appointments, including Legal Adviser to the Department of State (2005-2009) under Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice, and Senior Associate Counsel to the President and Legal Adviser to the National Security Council at the White House (2001-2005).
    - Bellinger, John - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file JohnBellinger.mov)
  - Benchakroun, Brahim, 2012-07-12; 1:38:53
    Brahim Benchakroun, male, age 32, Moroccan, was held in Guantanamo for nearly three years before he was released to Morocco in August 2004 at age 24. In April 2014, he was killed while fighting in Syria.
    - Benchakroun, Brahim - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file BrahimBenchakrounShadowed.mov)
  - Benchellali, Mourad, interview 1, 2009-08-09; 2:33:53
    Mourad Benchellali, male, age 28, French, was detained in Guantanamo from January 17, 2002 until July 26, 2004, when he was returned to France. He is currently public speaking in France, in the hope that by hearing his story, young people will not join ISIS or participate in suicide attacks.
    - Benchellali, Mourad, interview 1 - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MouradBenchellali.mov)
    - Benchellali, Mourad, interview 1 - short clip - HowtoFightRadicalIslam (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MouradBenchellali_HowtoFightRadicalIslam.mp4)
    - Benchellali, Mourad, interview 1 - short clip - Interrogations (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MouradBenchellali_Interrogations.mp4)
    - Benchellali, Mourad, interview 1 - short clip - Nightmares (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MouradBenchellali_Nightmares.mp4)
    - Benchellali, Mourad, interview 1 - short clip - PsychologicalWarfare (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MouradBenchellali_PsychologicalWarfare.mp4)
    - Benchellali, Mourad, interview 1 - short clip - reliefatAmericans (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MouradBenchellali_reliefatAmericans.mp4)
    - Benchellali, Mourad, interview 1 - short clip - TurningMyGuantrienceintoSomethingPositive (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MouradBenchellali_TurningMyGuantrienceintoSomethingPositive.mp4)
  - Benchellali, Mourad, interview 2, 2015-07-17; 2:06:25
    - Benchellali, Mourad, interview 2 - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MouradBenchellali2.mov)
  - Berenson, Bradford, 2015-09-11; 2:01:17
    Bradford Berenson, male, age 50, was Associate Counsel to President George W. Bush (2001-2003), and worked on the authorization for military commissions, detainee and anti-terrorism litigation, and the creation of the Department of Homeland Security.
    - Berenson, Bradford - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file BradfordBerenson.mov)
    - Berenson, Bradford - short clip - If We Could Take Back the Iraq War We Would (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BradfordBerenson_If We Could Take Back the Iraq War We Would.mp4)
    - Berenson, Bradford - short clip - Legal Precedents vs. the Temper of the Times (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BradfordBerenson_Legal Precedents vs. the Temper of the Times.mp4)
    - Berenson, Bradford - short clip - Obama Agrees with a Bush Policy (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BradfordBerenson_Obama Agrees with a Bush Policy.mp4)
  - Berg, Thomas, 2012-05-16; 1:05:30
    Thomas Berg, male, age 60, helped the Defense Department set up war crimes tribunals for captured al-Qaeda and Taliban prisoners after 9/11. The tribunals were based on the Uniform Code of Military Justice and the Geneva Conventions, but the Pentagon civilian leadership rejected them. He also served as Judge Advocate General, military legal adviser, to Gen. Rick Baccus in Guantanamo.
    - Berg, Thomas - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file ThomasBerg.mov)
    - Berg, Thomas - short clip - WeAlwaysRegretItLater (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TomBerg_WeAlwaysRegretItLater.mp4)
    - Berg, Thomas - short clip - WeAlwaysRegretItLaterw2gqt (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TomBerg_WeAlwaysRegretItLaterw2gqt.mp4)
    - Berg, Thomas - short clip - WeWereNaive (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TomBerg_WeWereNaive.mp4)
    - Bezri, Felice - short clip - CompleteDifferentPerson (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FeliceBezri_CompleteDifferentPerson.mp4)
    - Bezri, Felice - short clip - DetaineesTrainingInterrogatorsandInterpreters (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FeliceBezri_DetaineesTrainingInterrogatorsandInterpreters.mp4)
    - Bezri, Felice - short clip - RecoveringFromGuantanamo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file FeliceBezri_RecoveringFromGuantanamo.mp4)
  - Boudella, Haj, 2009-08-07; 1:44:36
    Haj Boudella, male, age 49, an Algerian-born Bosnian citizen, was detained in Guantanamo from January 20, 2002 until December 16, 2008 when he returned to his family in Bosnia after the landmark Supreme Court decision Boumediene v. Bush.
    - Boudella, Haj - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file HajBoudella.mov)
    - Boudella, Haj - short clip - contributiononly (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file HajBoudella_contributiononly.mp4)
    - Boudella, Haj - short clip - Helpless (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Haj_Helpless.mp4)
    - Boudella, Haj - short clip - PlantaTree (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file HajBoudella_PlantaTree.mp4)
    - Boudella, Haj - short clip - RedCross (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Haj_RedCross.mp4)
  - Boumediene, Lakhdar, 2009-08-13; 1:54:05
    Lakhdar Boumediene, male, age 43, Algerian, was detained in Guantanamo from January 20, 2002 until May 15, 2009, when he was released to France. A federal judge ruled that he was not being lawfully held and ordered his release on Nov. 20, 2008, but he was not released for another six months.
    - Boumediene, Lakhdar - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file LakhdarBoumediene.mov)
  - Bourdon, William, 2017-06-30; 0:27:01
    William Bourdon, male, age 60, was the lawyer for French detainees Nizar Sassi and Mourad Benchellali, and assisted in their release back to France in 2004, represented them later when they were accused of criminal association with a terrorist organization, and filed a case in French court against the U.S. for their torture.
    - Bourdon, William - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file WilliamBourdon.mov)
  - Bowman, Marion (Spike), 2011-03-10; 1:26:27
    Marion (Spike) Bowman, male, age 66, is the former Senior Counsel to the FBI, and the former Deputy National Counter Intelligence Executive.
    - Bowman, Marion (Spike) - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MarionSpikeBowman.mov)
    - Bowman, Marion (Spike) - short clip - HowtoTreatPrisoners (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file SpikeBowman_HowtoTreatPrisoners.mp4)
    - Bowman, Marion (Spike) - short clip - ToldtoPoundSand (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file SpikeBowman_ToldtoPoundSand.mp4)
    - Bowman, Marion (Spike) - short clip - WeHavetoMoveForward (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file SpikeBowman_WeHavetoMoveForward.mp4)
  - Bradley, Yvonne, 2010-12-05; 1:31:58
    Yvonne Bradley, female, age unknown, was a United States Air Force Attorney who vigorously represented former detainee, Binyam Mohamed, a former British resident who went on hunger strike to protest against the conditions at Guantanamo. All charges were dropped by the U.S. Government.
    - Bradley, Yvonne - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file YvonneBradley.mov)
    - Bradley, Yvonne - short clip - FirstMeeting (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file YvonneBradley_FirstMeeting.mp4)
    - Bradley, Yvonne - short clip - FirstMeeting (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file YvonneBradley_FirstMeeting.mp4)
    - Bradley, Yvonne - short clip - SharingACandyBar (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file YvonneBradley_SharingACandyBar.mp4)
  - Brant, David, 2011-03-11; 1:26:36
    David Brant, male, age 58, was the Director of the Naval Criminal Investigative Service from 1997 through 2005. He reported questionable interrogation techniques to Alberto Mora, then General Counsel of the Navy.
    - Brant, David - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file DavidBrant.mov)
    - Brant, David - short clip - MoraPutHisCareerontheLine (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file DavidBrant_MoraPutHisCareerontheLine.mp4)
  - Bryson, Jennifer, 2011-12-21; 2:12:47
    Jennifer Bryson, female, age 44, was an interrogator at Guantanamo Bay from 2004-2006, and the first female team chief. She has since written articles arguing that the U.S. should reject torture and use rapport-based interrogation.
    - Bryson, Jennifer - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file JenniferBryson.mov)
    - Bryson, Jennifer - short clip - ChannelingForGood (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file JenniferBryson_ChannelingForGood.mp4)
    - Bryson, Jennifer - short clip - QuestionableInterrogationTechniques (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file JenniferBryson_QuestionableInterrogationTechniques.mp4)
    - Bryson, Jennifer - short clip - SpeakingOutAgainstTorture (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file JenniferBryson_SpeakingOutAgainstTorture.mp4)
  - Buehn, Bob, 2011-10-22; 2:06:38
    Bob Buehn, male, age 60, was commander of the Guantanamo Bay Naval Base from 2000 to 2003, and helped establish the Joint Task Force Guantanamo.
    - Buehn, Bob - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file BobBuehn.mov)